<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain Development Funding on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</title>
    <link>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain Development Funding on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hold while Building</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/hodl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/hodl/</guid>
      <description>As with other FOSS domains, developers are probably users. In Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s case, this means that early developers may well have been holders of some BTC while it appreciated in value by orders of magnitude. Developers who held a significant amount of BTC through the price increases may now be independently wealthy and able to continue contributing without a need to generate an income from this or any other activity.
For early developers of a young blockchain project, obtaining some of the underlying asset makes sense if one believes that one&amp;rsquo;s efforts will help to increase its value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donations and Patronage</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/donations/</guid>
      <description>Donation based funding is familiar from other FOSS and CBPP domains - sustaining projects like VLC media player and Wikipedia (through the funding of the Wikimedia foundation). In the cryptocurrency space, informal ad hoc donations are relatively common. For example, Andreas Antonopoulos (Blockchain educator) received $1.5 million in BTC donations after revealing that he was not wealthy and being mocked for it. Vitalik Buterin (Ethereum co-founder) has distributed some 1,000 ETH donations on twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premines and ICOs</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/premine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/premine/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, many blockchain projects have been setting up their common pool resource so that it is able to fund its own development, either initially or on an ongoing basis. The remainder of this section reviews the various mechanisms through which a blockchain can fund its own development.
A premine refers to allocating some proportion of the tokens before the launch of the network, typically including these allocations in the genesis block when the blockchain launches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Reward Funding</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/blockreward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/development-funding/blockreward/</guid>
      <description>Some blockchains utilize a portion of ongoing block rewards to fund development. In the same way that miners are rewarded for the hashpower security they provide, those who build the infrastructure can also be rewarded for their work on an ongoing basis. This model is good for aligning the incentives of developers (or those who can expect to draw on the development funding) with the long term interests of the network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>