<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organizing and Funding Software Production on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</title>
    <link>/software-production/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organizing and Funding Software Production on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/software-production/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic motivation and Extrinsic rewards</title>
      <link>/software-production/intrinsic-extrinsic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software-production/intrinsic-extrinsic/</guid>
      <description>One concept from the Psychological literature relevant here is that of intrinsic motivation, which means being motivated by some inherent interest in the task and the satisfaction its completion will bring. Extrinsic motivation means being motivated by some external and separable outcome (e.g. getting paid). The difference between intrinsic and extrinsic motivation has been demonstrated experimentally (Deci, 1972) by asking participants to engage in some task like solving puzzles and controlling whether they receive an external reward (they are paid to puzzle) or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Software Industry</title>
      <link>/software-production/software-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software-production/software-industry/</guid>
      <description>While intrinsic motivation may be a factor in the behavior of company employees, this cannot be assumed. What can be assumed is that the payment workers receives and the importance of that money to them marginalizes any role for intrinsic motivation. The individual&amp;rsquo;s will is subjugated to that of the corporate hierarchy, at least within certain time periods where the employee is &amp;ldquo;at work&amp;rdquo;.
The lack of intrinsic motivation means that workers may not actually complete their work if they can get away with it, which necessitates means for the corporation to ensure that they get what they are paying for from workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Production</title>
      <link>/software-production/foss-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software-production/foss-production/</guid>
      <description>FOSS starts from the basis of having all of the code on the commons, removing the possibility that anyone can seek to profit by restricting access to it. Anyone is free to use it and build on it, to extend it or turn it into something else. The ease with which a FOSS project can be forked and taken in an alternative direction limits the degree to which users or developers have to tolerate any behaviour they dislike from the entity which is producing the software - whether that&amp;rsquo;s some odious new feature or an order to do something which contradicts one&amp;rsquo;s own preference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Governance</title>
      <link>/software-production/foss-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software-production/foss-governance/</guid>
      <description>The defining feature of FOSS governance is the fact that the product is commons based and equally accessible to all parties. There is relatively little friction involved in forking a codebase and taking two versions of a piece of software in different directions. The ownership of Intellectual Property (IP), which determines who is allowed to develop and exploit proprietary software, has only limited significance. In FOSS projects IP considerations are typically limited to the ownership of non-vital assets such as names/trademarks, domains and hosting services (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>