<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commons Constituencies on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</title>
    <link>/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commons Constituencies on Peer Production on the Crypto Commons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of Work Miners</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/miners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/miners/</guid>
      <description>PoW miners of Bitcoin are presently incentivized by receiving rewards (newly minted coins plus transaction fees) for each block they produce. The PoW miner subsidy represents inflation which every holder of the asset is indirectly paying for through the relative decrease in the value of their own holdings. Importantly, Bitcoin has a fixed inflationary schedule which will see the rate of inflation drop (half) at specified points in the future, until the limit of 21 million BTC is reached and no more new coins are produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Developers</title>
      <link>/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/foss-for-cpr/commons-constituencies/developers/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain developers can implement a change to their software which changes the consensus rules, but this will only take effect if the other constituencies apply this update. For some networks, there is only a single viable node implementation, and in those cases the other constituencies have limited choice in whether to accept or reject any proposed changes to the consensus rules. Rejecting a change may mean abandoning the chain which is being actively maintained in favor of a chain whose software is no longer updated, or is updated with weaker quality controls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>